[Music playing]
Somewhere in time and space, Mike Nelson and his robot pals
are caught in an endless chase.
Pursued by a woman whose name is Pearl,
an evil gal who wants to rule the world.
She threw a few things in her purse.
And in her rocket ship, she hunts
him all across the universe.
I'll get you!
I'll send him cheesy movies.
The worst I can find.
He'll have to sit and watch them all.
And I'll monitor his mind.
Now keep in mind Mike can't control
where the movies begin or end.
He'll try to keep his sanity with the help of his robot
friends.
Robot rules called "Kabob."
You're on.
Juicy.
Tom Servo.
Check me out.
I am ripped.
[Music playing]
If you're wondering how he eats and breathes
and other science facts, just repeat to yourself,
it's just a show.
You should really just relax.
Oh, Mystery Science Theater 3000.
[Music playing]
[Roaring]
[Clanking]
[Beeping]
Oh.
Well, thanks, Servo.
That was really great.
Ah.
You betcha, Crow.
Stop in any time.
Sure.
A kissing booth?
What for?
Well, I got to come up with some capital
so I can open my chain of kissing booths.
Oh.
Well, what kind of kisses do you have?
Well, let's see.
I've got a full-in-the-mouth landed ration of kiss.
That's kind of nice.
We have an unwelcome opportunistic Christmas party
kiss.
That's popular.
How about the cigarette-y kiss from a woman named Vi?
It's one of my favorites.
No.
You know, I was thinking of kind of a dry, perfunctory grandma
kiss.
Well, OK, but no tongue.
Ew.
No, no.
I mean, I don't have a tongue, so don't be disappointed.
Oh.
Well, that's a good thing.
Come on over here, honey.
There you go.
That'll be $49.95 cash or meet your credit card.
We'll be right back.
You know, I don't mean to complain.
It was dry and perfunctory, but it seemed more ant-like
than grandma-like.
Really?
[Music playing]
[Humming]
Tom?
Later.
Practicing.
Like it.
Aw, come on.
Give someone else a crack at those lips.
Ah.
Whoa.
May I help you?
Nope.
Got it all under control.
Thanks.
Ok.
Well, let me know if you need anything.
Now, Tom, the--
Hey, wait a minute.
What are you doing here?
Yeah.
Well, I'm installing three handsets,
local switching bay for six lines, all called PA,
and full duplex conferencing.
Oh, great.
I'm guessing a woman in a castle sent you up here?
Yep.
Woman, albino, then hairy fella.
Sure.
Mike Nelson, call on line two.
Mike Nelson.
Right here?
Ok.
Yellow?
Nelson.
Good.
You're there.
Yeah.
What can I do for you, Pearl?
No.
It's what you can do for me.
See, I'm setting up an all-station phone
conference for now.
Can you make it?
Good.
I want to get you up to speed on our new state-of-the-art phone
system, which will make taking over the world easier
through more efficient officeing.
Ok.
Office away.
Hang on.
I'll get the others on the line.
Oh.
Um, yellow?
Hello?
All right.
Would you talk to me?
Officer.
Yeah.
Ok.
We have a line around the corner.
Let's see.
Hello.
Can you hear me?
I'm having a little-- can you hear me?
Hello?
I can hear you.
Hello, are you there?
Hello?
Hello.
All I'm getting is a--
It's very hard to hear.
I can't hear you.
Why don't you hang up?
It's like a box or something.
Turn down the radio.
I'm going to get you up.
It's like a box or something.
Dial dial star 69.
Hello?
[Knocking]
Damn it.
Hello?
I can hear you.
Can you hear me?
Hello?
I can barely hear you.
OK, orbiting doorknobs.
I guess you need a lesson in how to use a simple phone.
So before you start your painful movie, Space Children,
I order you to watch this painful short feature
century 21 calling on how simple the phone of the future is.
Hello?
I don't know.
I can hear you.
Hello?
Please?
I can't hear you.
Oh, boys.
Hello?
I have a special call for you.
Oh.
Oh, boy.
Hello?
Special call for the--
[grunting]
Into the theater, you.
Hello?
Movie time!
[Buzzing]
[Laughing]
[Loud bang]
[
Ah, these monorail designers, they have a one-track mind.
What do you lash out at?
I don't know.
Oh, here comes my train.
I got to catch it.
It's my train.
[Stammers]
Never mind.
Isn't it great there's only white people here?
[Sighs]
[Beeping]
We're crushing pigeons.
It's fun.
Yes, Seattle.
Like a beautiful child growing up free and wild.
I'm going insane.
I really am.
[Laughing]
I'm going insane.
[Scatting]
Look, there's Pearl Jam.
A kid in a Jack Nicklaus culture?
Oh, boy.
This is our first visit to Pat Boone World.
All passengers must leave the train at this terminal.
All passengers turn to your left as you leave the train.
I'm driving the monorail drunk so what?
Let's start Microsoft here.
[Splat]
[Laughing]
The only bathroom in the fair is up there.
Well, I'm glad to know that the future has constant organ music.
[Humming]
Oh.
[Singing]
[Humming]
Eating Mark Simpson hair.
Morrissey's Wild Mouse.
Well.
Yeah, I guess.
We have Mike Nelson visits the fair.
[Laughing]
[Honking]
Frank Lloyd Wright.
Oh.
Oh, look at that.
Great.
Gifts from Germany.
What's that?
Bronchwager, cars with heaters that don't work,
and identification papers.
No problem.
OK, you pull.
It'll symbolize our looming marriage.
Hey, get your own mouth suit made.
That's OK.
Just touch me wherever you want.
That's fine.
Oh, yeah, that's fine.
Yeah, that's my microphone.
Come on, let's go grope that Eskimo.
Damn.
What's in your pocket?
Oh, come on.
You're gay and you know it.
Hi.
You have a weird red spot on your head.
[Laughing]
The Church of Science.
Do they need region-style directors?
You know, I just think if we went back to the Peep Show
for a few minutes, it would be really good.
I mean, it's kind of science when you think about it.
And anatomy and stuff.
I mean--
Ren and Stimpy music.
Polyester, how can it work for you?
These are actual gel molecules.
What a beautiful thing.
What a beautiful complex carbohydrate.
It's a brand new 1962 double helix.
It also goes round and round pretty.
How do animals learn?
Well, as long as they learn to taste good,
I don't really care.
Here, you're a geek.
Why don't you bite the head off this bird?
Now, we roast this squab with new potatoes
and it's only $5.99.
Okay, folks, I'm writing code for a Java applet here.
This pigeon also does caricatures at parties.
Hey, Robert Devolvis, it's the World's Fair.
Celebrating Pride Week at the fair.
I'm gay!
I feel good about me!
I don't know, I just seem to be drawn to that German exhibit.
Just mow down the old people.
That's fine, kids.
Hey, hey, we're young and perky.
Get the hell out of our way!
Here is a world of communication.
Who are you?
Tattered for your needs of today and tomorrow.
Bringing together the world's best of the world.
Bringing together all people in a new era of understanding.
Accept the annoying poor.
Introducing the Rotary Phone!
I'm in the phone pavilion, dear, and I'm wearing a fright wig.
Keeping in touch by means of the amazing new Bell Boy
is the Bell System's answer today for doctors, salesmen, delivery men,
or anyone who must be available at all times in the fast-paced world of century 21.
When someone calls and you are out, you can be reached by dialing your Bell Boy code number.
Of course, this assumes that anyone wants to call you.
My pacemaker!
When you get a signal on the Bell Boy, you can go to a phone to call your officer home and get the message.
Call me later, toots, okay?
This is the automatic dialer.
Just listen for dial tone, insert a number card, and press the start bar.
Then run!
The Bell System automatic dialer dials for you more quickly and easily than you can do it yourself.
Here, you tell mom I'm pregnant.
Numbers you call frequently can be punched on small plastic cards.
Push button phoning!
Thank you.
Yeah, let's head over to the Steak and Martini pavilion.
Hi, this is the Bell System's new touch tone dialing.
With this indicator, you see how many seconds you saved the new way.
Let's try it!
Okay, I'll race you.
In 40 years, there will still be a $2 surcharge for this service,
despite the technology having proliferated everywhere on the planet.
Sorry.
I beat you.
Yeah, beating me. Real big victory.
Welcome to our exhibit.
I'm glad to have this opportunity to tell you about the telephone switching center of tomorrow.
The electronic central office, which is made possible by the magic of the transistor
and other tiny but amazing devices invented by the Bell Telephone Laboratory.
I'm Sharon Lawrence.
Imagine if you can an electronic brain operating at millionth of a second speed.
No.
I say brain because the new electronic central office will almost spin for itself.
It will not only carry out instructions and dial into it,
it will also remember instructions you provided earlier.
These memory features will offer many convenient services I'm sure you'll be delighted with.
For one thing, you'll be able to reach frequently called numbers by dialing only two digits.
All you'll have to do is give the telephone company a list of the numbers you dial most frequently.
The electronic brain's memory will do the rest.
The fuhrer will like that.
To see how it works, please watch the screen.
Wait.
That phone's hanging on the wall. What will they think of next?
Is your turn to phone grandma?
Now let's see.
No.
Alright.
Now let's say you want to call your mother who lives in Des Moines.
Why?
You call her fairly often, so the telephone company has assigned 5-3 as your special number for making this call.
When you dial the 5 and the 3, the electronic central office's brain says,
"Oh, something special. Search its memory for what those two digits represent."
And ask the area code plus the phone number in Des Moines for you.
Grandma's Barbara Bush.
Hello?
Hello, grandma!
Where's my money?
Ever been invited out for an evening and had to turn it down because you're expecting an extra special call?
No.
Well, the electronic central office will solve that problem for you too.
When you do go out, it will be a simple matter to have your calls transferred.
All you'll have to do is dial a special code which tells the equipment's brain you want your calls transferred.
And then dial the telephone number where you can be reached.
The hit is ordered.
Our amazing electronic central office will take it from there.
Then you can go off with your drinking and pill popping.
I think it's a wonderful call for you.
[phone ringing]
That must be JFK.
Hello?
Diane?
No, this isn't Diane. It's Linda.
Linda?
What gives?
This is Jim Morton. I was calling Diane Brown.
Oh, yes, she's here.
She had her calls transferred to my house.
We're lovers now.
Hi, Jim.
And what about those times someone has tried to call you and your line is busy?
Yeah!
We thought of that too.
We're the best.
Fine, Sarah. That's fine.
I'll have the information for you at the meeting next Wednesday.
[beep]
When you hear the beep tone on your telephone, you know someone else is trying to reach you.
Sarah, will you hold on just a minute? Someone else is trying to reach me.
All you do is flick the switch hook to hold the first call while you take the second.
Hello?
Hello, dear. I was just talking to Sarah.
But I left her hanging. I love doing that.
I see.
Okay, dear, would you tell Fred next time he's in town, he's to bring Helen, right?
And a body bag.
Bye, dear.
You flick the button back and go on with your first call.
[phone ringing]
Hello, Sarah? That was Burt calling.
Easy as pie, isn't it?
And here's another feature you're going to find handy.
Now look, Sarah Jane knows a lot more about that than I do.
Why don't we get her on the line and find out?
Okay, just a minute.
Want someone else on the line?
No.
That's easy too.
Flip the switch button, then dial a code number and the number you want.
And presto.
Well, on Dante, maybe.
Soon you'll have all your friends hanging up on you and dreading your calls.
Hello, Jane? This is Martha.
Listen, I have Sarah on the line and we want to know what to do about--
About what?
As we look to the future, we have many extras for tomorrow's telephone users.
One day you may be able to call home and automatically turn off the oven.
If you're dumb enough to have left it on.
Or from a public telephone a couple of hundred miles away--
Tell your mistress you can't get away from your wife.
Turn on your home air conditioner and have the house nice and cool when you return from your hot trip.
It may even be possible to call and water the lawn during that dry spell when you are many miles away on vacation.
How do you like it when the lawn piddles on you?
I called your blow comb, honey.
Sounds fantastic, doesn't it?
But it is all possible because of the basic research our scientists and engineers at the Bell Telephone Laboratories are doing to make your service better day by day.
From their work has come breakthrough after breakthrough in science, providing the intricate devices that lie at the heart of your telephone service of tomorrow.
Through the invention of better things, we are trying very hard to give you the kind of telephone service you want and need.
And we think you'll agree, after seeing the many exhibits we have here, there is no end to telephone progress now or in century 21.
That evening the oppressive cloud of the phone company hung heavy over the world.
The phones! They're coming!
Wow, that is one impressive corndog stand.
I like the giant bowl of soup exhibit here.
It's a vicious gang of air franstuituses.
It smells like something from Side 5 of Sandinista.
But you can't escape death!
Don't examine your soul, just get speed dialing!
You fuck!
Someday you will ache like I ache!
It's just phones, jeez!
Where did we park?
We died, we're in heaven!
You know, look, it's just a peep show, it's not like I want to cheat on you or anything.
For a written transcript of this program send $5 adrenal graphics.
He's doing that little fella from the short film.
It's pretty entertaining really.
Well, I think it's time. Let's go.
Ah, there. Very nice.
So, lunch? Again? Why sure!
Yum!
Live from Zermatt!
George Bailey's in trouble! Again!
The architecturally rigid Space Children!
Darlene was arraigned in Superior Court, County of Los Angeles.
Music by Rick Wakeman here.
Wow, there goes the ice cream truck. I just don't have the energy to chase it.
Enjoy our hockey stick names.
What the hell? Hey, that jerk over there's got a camera filming me.
Oh, wow. The movie just dumped a whole pallet load of actors on us.
And Jackie Coogan rules over them all.
Okay, what is there going to be a test on this later?
I call unnecessary use of ellipses there. Five yard penalty.
Awesome download.
It's Linda Hunt!
These people do not deserve pictures. They're too hideous to show on screen.
Mike, I want you to call me Farsiad Edouard from now on.
Okay, Farsiad.
I'm a Space Children with a Y, thank you.
Now if you'll open your hymnals to page 35.
Nellie Manley, whose real name is Sissy Macho.
Yeah, meet me at the corner of Van and Cleve.
Hey, Pa! Pa! Why am I floating in space?
All and all the time.
Wow. I apologize.
Starry, starry, Jack Arnold.
Amen.
One bottle of beer on the wall, one bottle of beer.
Bugsy Siegel rides with his family to start Las Vegas.
So the guy from North by Northwest married Ruth Bader Ginsburg.
I guess.
Is it much further?
A few miles.
Do you have enough gas?
I got plenty.
They already blasted a hole through the seat cover.
Okay, we've seen the ocean now. Let's head back to Iowa.
Wow, there's a silky stuck in the oil slick.
Oh, that's ocean and sand. I feel as if I were in another world.
You won't mind it. Wait and see.
Look, man, we gotta stick together.
Tell your mother it's gonna be swell living at the ocean.
Sure, Mom. Dad's gonna buy me some flippers and I'll let you wear them.
That's a kid with a Flemish accent.
The Don King State Forest.
Whoa, Dad wasn't kidding about his gas.
I'm getting worried about him. This points to a serious medical ailment.
I mean...
Mom, listen. Listen to what?
It's Brian Eno, Mom.
Dad, don't you hear it?
Hey, what's up?
Man, the old man's deaf to his own flatulence.
Sand crabs are using their death ray.
Hey, they're out of gas.
What in the world?
I warned you.
Honey, I got more than half a tank left.
This electrical system isn't working.
Dad, listen.
Not now, son. I gotta figure this out. There's something wrong here.
Mom, look at this, dear.
Never talk, ever.
That's funny, bro. It's working now.
But Dad, up there.
What?
It wasn't a jet. It wasn't anything like a jet.
Children, will you stop chattering?
Stop trying to form a bond with us. We had you. Isn't that enough?
Driving on the beach with the kids in the car.
Nice rabbit's man.
They drove a thousand miles to get their pictures developed, huh?
Dave Bruce to Oakland Electronic Company, San Francisco. I'm assigned to Colonel Manley.
I'm Sergeant Womanley.
First to David. Family of three.
Wow. They're due to be executed.
Is this the last of the bunch?
Yes, that's so.
Here, let them through.
Thank you, Maytag repairman.
Okay, go ahead.
Where's Unit 3? We're going to live there.
Yes, ma'am. Keep going right over the rise. You'll find Unit 3 on your left.
Thanks.
Russian agents stealthily approach the guard point, see the stop signs and turn around defeated.
Tornado Magnet Trailer Park welcomes you.
Yeah, a lot of loose meat sandwiches eaten here.
Honey, now don't get mad, but I forgot our trailer.
Don't.
Well, this is it, honey.
The end of all hope and joy.
Try to make the best of it.
Come on, kids, let's get out.
Here's the last box of your resentment for me.
Well, I put away most of the clothes. There's good closet space, anyhow.
It's not so bad.
Sure. You like living on the beach.
It's only temporary, Annie.
It doesn't matter. The sand's going to drift in and ruin everything, anyhow.
Look, honey, I've driven over 500 miles today.
Tomorrow I start a new job, an important job.
I'm a little tired myself.
Of course. I'm sorry.
I'm just tight and bitter.
I guess I'm just homesick for San Francisco.
Great life in the Castro district.
Well, where is it?
San Francisco? It's up the coast, I think.
Launching platform.
Sit on the beach?
Probably. Somewhere on the beach.
Everything's on the beach here.
When's the first task?
I don't know. Soon. Maybe this week.
Will it work?
Look, I'm trying to avoid you with menial work, okay?
It's got to.
It's got to do a job better than theirs.
So if they start needing...
Dave, what you said about its accuracy?
We just got here, honey. I don't know any answers.
But you, your company, you worked on it for months.
I worked on one pot out of 35,000 pots.
It's much more complicated than just an intercontinental missile.
It's not like shopping or makeup.
Is ours the only one?
We don't think so.
I enjoy our warm chats about civil defense, honey.
It's almost funny, isn't it?
I mean, they're children living in the middle of all of this.
Would you have wanted me to say no
when the company insisted I come in?
Doc, she's going to hit you.
No, it's not.
No, I'm just tired.
I'm sorry.
Well, let's go out and find Buddy Kim.
Okay. I could use some air.
Let's see. What else can I hate?
I wish the children hadn't wandered off.
You think it's dangerous down there in the rocks?
No. Besides, you know how the boys love the beach.
The ocean, the rocks,
everything makes me feel so unimportant to myself.
Well, you'll like it here.
Where do you meet the others?
Then you'll feel really unimportant.
I guess we better get back to straighten things out.
The sand is probably destroying everything in there.
Mr. Brewster?
Hi.
I'm your new roommate.
I'm Mr. James, Security Officer for the command.
I just heard from the gate you'd arrived.
This is my wife.
How do you do?
I hope you'll be comfortable here, Mr. Brewster.
Thank you.
I'm glad I caught you.
I hope it won't be inconvenient,
but you're the last member to arrive
and the Colonel's giving a welcome briefing
I think you'd like to attend.
If you don't mind, Mr. Brewster?
No, of course not.
You'll come back as soon as you can.
Sure, I will.
And if me and the kids aren't there when you get back,
just accept them.
Well, time to throw myself on the bed and heave in sobs.
Hello.
I'm Freida Johnson.
I live in the next trailer.
I'm Ann Brewster.
How do you do?
I'm your Ethel Mertz.
You just arrived.
Everything certainly is strange and different here.
I know just how you feel.
I thought I'd die the first few weeks away
from my folks and friends.
It's the feeling of living so close to the end of the world, maybe.
After what?
You don't think of it like that.
Do you have any children?
Two boys.
They're on the beach somewhere.
How old are they?
Twelve and ten.
Oh, that'll be great for Edie.
She's eleven.
Well, I better get my laundry on the line.
Oh, by the way, we're having a weenie roast out here tonight.
Why don't you come?
It's really for the kids.
Oh, that'd be very nice.
Thank you so much.
Good, then we'll see you later.
And slowly lock the doors and hide in the closet.
[Music]
We're almost home.
We've hit Yosemite.
[Panting]
Here, catch!
Just a minute!
Come on, run!
Let me get over by a sharper rock.
Nice throw.
You only had an hour to line it up.
Hey, bud, come here!
Ow!
Gee, bud, I bet it's a real cave.
Yeah.
This is a perfect place to make our delicious Roquefort cheese.
Grendel, you home?
It's a naturally occurring comedy club.
Gee, do you think we discovered this cave?
Maybe.
What a day.
First that thing in the sky and now this place.
Then we played with a ball? Wow.
Are you scared of what you saw?
You?
No.
Do you think it'll come back?
I hope so.
So do I.
You bet.
Then we can show it to Dad and prove we weren't making things up.
What happened?
Kind of spookier.
Yeah.
It's all dark back there. Maybe at least another cave.
You better stay here again.
Wow. Look at that giant cave squid stinging him to death, sucking the blood right out of him. Cool.
Hi.
You scared me.
We're the children of the damned you've heard about.
We found our cave.
We didn't know anyone knew about it.
We have secret club meetings here.
My name's Edie Johnson.
I saw you move in next door to us.
This guy.
Who are you?
I'm Bud Brewster. This is my kid brother Ken.
Hi.
This is Buster, Tim, George and Helen.
I'm too old for this group really.
Your father wanted to work here?
Yeah, he's what you call a technician.
He knows everything about orbits and satellites and hydrogen and missiles and warheads.
So does mine.
Have you seen it yet, the Thunder?
It's the biggest one in the world.
It's a six-stage rocket.
It takes a satellite with a hydrogen warhead and the satellite will be hundreds of miles up in a year.
It's a
Remind me to never be a child.
Lord of the Flies action figures.
Is your mom sitting back in your trailer depressed and warning the life she can never have?
Mine too.
Say, have any of you said the darndest thing lately?
Two billion dollars and we made a poll.
There it is.
Wow.
Isn't it terrific?
Yeah, it sure is.
The Edward Teller Home Security System.
Magnificent.
All right, beat it kids.
You know you don't belong here.
Okay, okay.
I was only showing them the Thunder.
Come on, let's move.
All right.
I'm with you.
But don't you moon me.
Wow.
Toss me that warhead.
Here, throw it to me.
Catch it.
Does anyone else think this isn't much fun?
Hey, look up there.
What is it, son?
It's a
It's cleaning that cave like a white tornado.
I saw nothing like this in Antwerp.
Come on.
Let's watch them come-on-ing.
Hey, hey, we're the children.
People say we children around.
We're too busy children-ing.
Okay, yeah.
That's enough.
Thank you.
Children.
Yes, I will take money from my dad's wallet and send it to soupy sales.
Matt, you can call me Ray.
No.
You're on warning.
Wow, the space people are passing a gallstone.
With pinpoint accuracy.
Hang on, Neil's bore is using the toaster.
Let's just wait a minute, gentlemen.
Lights will be on in a minute, probably a fuse.
Check 'em, please.
General, at this point in time, I am scared.
Yep, scared, sir.
If I could just graze that 9-pin, get the spare.
Bud's got the Steve McGarrett hair going.
We disproved God while you were gone.
There.
That's better.
Now what was I mesmerizing you with?
Sorry for the interruption, gentlemen.
It's nice to know we're no longer in the dark.
Sir!
Ha ha ha ha ha!
Getting back to the launching of the Thunderer.
Mermaids are really hitting today.
Hi, Mayor.
This will complete the Thunderer.
Sessions presents Bald Gold.
Man, the moon doggy's really gone to sea, man.
I'm washing my socks.
How's the fishing, Colonel?
Dr. Warman.
Any luck?
Ha ha.
Not a bite.
Do sailfish hit on bologna?
Wonderful day.
The sky looks so innocent.
What?
Doctor, will we succeed tomorrow?
I see no reason why not.
How time flies.
Seems like yesterday the first satellite orbited through space.
Yes.
Now we launch my godchild.
She's five.
I suppose people will get used to the Thunderer.
Its implications.
Hey, Dad.
Hello, son.
Hi, Dad.
Hi, Phyllis.
How's fishing, Dad?
Not very good.
Catch anything?
Probably the sniffles.
Water cold?
A little.
Come on, Phyllis, let's get dressed.
See you, kids.
Remember when sex wasn't a job?
Life's a wonderful thing, Doctor.
Let's hope we can preserve it for them.
So, you're a commie rat, huh?
What's going on?
Intestine stuffed with nitrates and pig snouts.
Hey, look, here.
Hey, watch it, kids, huh?
Come and get them while they're hot boys.
Plenty more with these game drums.
Oh, honey, just put them on the table.
We're up to here with hot dogs.
God, it's Uncle Fester in shorts.
Yeah, I know.
Well, if this parent teacher's meeting...
Ah!
...on the spot, they kept saying,
"When is it going to end?"
Year after year of racing, racing,
trying to find something bigger and better
to blow ourselves off the planet.
When they ask me these questions,
what do I tell them?
You just say to them that down there stands the Thunderer.
And what are we waiting for?
Hank, dear, let's not be serious tonight, huh?
Let's get to the wife swapping.
It's your first day here, Dave.
What's your viewpoint?
Same as my wife's.
In all its history, our country's never started a war.
The Thunderer is to prevent war.
I still say that when that satellite gets up there
with the Thunderer and it gets into its orbit, we should...
We should take a vacation.
That's what you need, Hank.
A nice vacation.
Hank could kill everybody if you let him.
Dave, why don't you and Hank take a swim, huh?
Come on, Johnson, let's take a dip with the kids.
What do you say?
That's a good idea.
Edie?
Yes, Daddy?
Want to go for a swim with me, honey?
Sure, Daddy, I'll go.
Oh, no, his shorts.
That's right, his horrible shorts.
I'd go, but I'm high.
I think I had too many hot dogs, Daddy.
I'd better not go for a swim.
How about the rest of you kids?
Anybody want to go for a dip?
Bud, Ken?
Francois, Abdul, Vyeshdoshlav.
Thanks, Dad.
Edie, I'll race you to the cliff.
Sure.
Our daughter sure got over her stomach.
Ain't gonna hurry, didn't she?
She sure did.
You ready for the big plunge?
Yeah, sure.
Hello, Joe.
Hi.
This is Peg and Joe Gamble and Brewster.
Nice to know you.
Hi.
Well, we're a little late, but then, of course, nobody invited us.
Joe, we were invited.
You fell asleep, don't you remember?
Joe, stop carrying that chip on your shoulder.
Well, he isn't feeling very well tonight, Freda.
My wife is just trying to be polite.
She means I'm tight.
Did you get that job, Joe?
No, I flunked a test.
Puked on the blue book.
Peg will have to go on bringing in the bankroll.
Please, Joe.
I'm done with roller derby.
Where's Jim?
Oh, he's with the other children.
He's always running off without telling us where he's going.
Wow.
If I were that kid's real father, I'd...
But you're not his father, and I'm not your wife,
so I can afford to tell you a few things that have been on my mind, Joe Gamble.
He's a spoiled brat.
He won't drink with me.
Him?
Where is he?
(Barks)
Him?
(Music)
Four, three, two, one, blast off!
Yay!
Oh, for God...
What?
Oh, for...
Oh, man.
Oh, okay, got to be careful around that.
Remember, don't turn it on until I say, okay?
What?
Turn it on?
No, I'll... I'll... I'll... I'll... I'll... I'll... I'll... I'll... I'll... I'll... I'll... I'll...
Model Rocketry, I'll show you Model Rocketry.
Hey, look at what I got.
(Thunder)
In fact, now that I think about it, does the word "model" make any sense at all?
No!
What I got going is way beyond model rockets.
I got a rocket!
Go get the monkey.
Yes.
Sure, at this point, I'm lagging behind the other superpowers in the race to dominate space,
but as soon as I launch my first monkey into space, there is going to be such...
I was scared to go into space.
Oh, weird training.
Now, shut up and get in the centrifuge.
Okay.
See, the way I figure it, I got a monkey.
Why not develop a space program around that monkey?
No reason at all.
Monkey in centrifuge, ma'am.
Of course, I can't take all the credit.
It was Brain Guy here who pointed out to me that we have a monkey.
Now, now, don't be modest.
You're the one who realized we have a monkey.
I suppose I did.
(Chuckles)
There's a sharp thing in my side.
How?
Oh, it's simply the pin that holds the passenger compartment to the centrifuge itself.
I don't suppose I...
(Screaming)
That was fun.
Let's do it again.
The point is, Nelson, you can just sit down because I got a space program.
(Laughing)
Come on now, big fella.
Let's take another ride.
(Singing)
Oh, don't turn it on.
(Laughing)
For Moby's sign, live and learn.
You might want to put out your shirt sleeve.
Yeah, oh, thanks.
We just blew you up.
Good deal.
Oh, they're trying to get as far away from Jackie Coogan in tiny shorts as possible.
Well, the pilot for Baywatch was very different from the series, wasn't it?
Has he ever eaten or been out in the sun at all?
Yep, we lose a kid a week doing this, but it's still fun.
A little help?
Yes, we're almost to Switzerland, then we'll be safe.
Oh, yes, Edie can wear her swimsuit another three or four years.
It's fine.
Poor kid.
We will name this new colony Budtown.
Well, they ran all the way to the Antarctic.
Where do we go?
Up this way.
Are you visiting Fred Flintstone at work?
Hey, a glowing challah.
Hey, guys, we got a new third base.
Two weenies, one with mustard.
You knew what would be here.
Did it tell you?
Yes.
It said, "I will be here."
Is he wearing a miniskirt?
I don't know.
You're going to be the leader.
You'll have to do what I tell you to.
I'm getting out of here.
I have an appointment with my broker.
He's strong for a man his age.
I can't move.
I think it's because of my allergies.
You can now.
Well, now I just don't want to.
Try.
Your thought commandeth you.
From now on, when I ask you to do something, we'll do it together.
Wow.
Yes, Bud.
Sure.
Sorry about the rock and all.
So I assume you kids are the all-powerful rulers of Earth?
Hey, kids, enjoy my silly putty qualities.
I can lift images off the funny papers for you.
We're married with children.
It's blaring away in there.
Hank, is Edie back yet?
Just a minute.
Good, yeah.
Yeah.
Oh, it's all right.
Thank you very much.
Where have you been?
Sorry, Mother.
I oughta wallop to both of you.
Wearing your mother like that, stay on till almost nine.
We were just on the beach.
You knew this was our first day here.
You made me walk up and down the beach hunting for you and your brother.
Dave, stop pounding at me.
Go get undressed.
Tell him, Bud.
Tell him.
Tell us what?
Bud's omnipotent.
We can tell him, can't we, Bud?
Blow and blob.
We need a decision on this one.
Yes, I know.
What's the matter?
What are you talking to yourself for?
You sick?
No, I'm all right.
I've just had nothing but hot dogs for eight days.
Weren't you gonna tell him, Bud?
I'm sick of wearing tough skins, Mom.
We found something that fell out of the sky this afternoon.
We know where it is.
The sky?
Bud's telling the truth.
I saw it too.
It fell out of the sky.
Well, you've gotta believe him.
How long did it take you to dream up that yarn?
I didn't dream it up.
You think a lot like that's gonna make it all right, huh?
For staying out until all hours?
It's not a lie.
Something's wrong.
I know it is.
Something is wrong.
Look, you're upsetting him by now.
Let's go to bed.
Come on.
Dad, you've gotta believe.
Believe what?
Some crazy story you made up for an excuse?
Listen, for two cents I...
Thou hast angered Bud.
Come on.
Come on, boy, come on.
Pork chop going through aorta.
Hang up your slippers.
There's a new dad in town.
It's not a lie, Dad.
Please sit down and listen to me.
You too, Mom.
Okay, first off, we've been running short of Captain Crunch lately.
We were coming back from the rocket site,
and all of a sudden we heard this strange sound.
Yeah?
Oh, that Rockford throws a great dinner party.
What are you doing here?
I'm ready.
She knows Dad.
Come on.
Don't make any trouble, Dad.
We know where you live.
The boy in the plastic trailer.
Let me just hop off the can.
I'll catch up with you guys.
Man, I can't believe they left without their spaz.
See you next week, Mrs. Robinson.
Where do you think you're going?
I asked you a question.
I was just going out for a walk.
You're a liar.
You're up to something.
Please, Joe, let me go.
I'll be back soon.
You're going nowhere except to bed.
I've got to go.
You little sneak.
Come back here.
We must be having Gilligan flashbacks.
Boy, the sun's strong tonight.
Hey, bud.
Dan, wait for me.
No.
This will be the fourth age group that's left me behind.
Come back here.
I'll break your neck.
It's really more of a disincentive.
Oh, right on my flask.
It looks like they found a new big kid to play with him.
He's going to use his coconut-powered spanking machine on me.
Hey, bud.
Wait for me.
A three-day binge of green beans.
So explain this, kids. This accent is free somehow.
This boy with glandular imbalance is life.
Come back here. I'll break your neck.
Oh, look, dad.
A full bottle of Jim Beam right there.
Come back here, Joe.
Say what you will.
A lot of stepfathers never take the time to get involved in their stepson's lives.
True.
Ooh, imagine having your butt whooped by Anverest.
Oh, that's nice.
Brought to you by the hate council.
Moses. Oh, sorry. Wrong guy.
I want you to get a hold of a man named Mr. Howell.
It's very important.
So are we still going to the father-son boy scout banquet next week?
Okay. Want to see the dead squirrel?
We brought you a nondescript B actor just like you asked, oh, powerful jelly brain.
Uh, glob lore the magnificent, this is my dad, Hank.
Uh-huh, uh-huh.
You know, he knows about your embezzling. Does that mean anything to you?
Uh, hang on just a second. Let me wiggle the rabbit ears here.
I'll just shake a little there.
Well, thank you for the nice cow flop, I guess, kids.
Okay, but you have to feed it and walk it. Having a blob is a big responsibility.
No, dad, no, you tore its leg off, dad. Jeez.
This blob is mine, kids gave this blob to me.
Uh, kids, it's laying eggs in my chest. Is that normal?
We now return to the littlest bodyguards.
Night, bud.
Have a good day at the office tomorrow.
Oh, I just watched Gilligan's Island.
Uh, you look different. Did you get haircuts?
Oh, Timmy.
Oh, his breath, even from here.
Don't cry, mom.
But I've got 30 cases of Smirnoff's I don't know what to do with.
I'm not crying, Tim.
Now he won't have to buy a new doorstop.
Get the most out of a shot by using it twice, I guess.
Edie.
Why don't you think of my woman-y role?
Hi, daddy.
Rooster, what's this all about? Where have you all been?
You see, Mr. Johnson, I thought I heard something on the beach and Edie saw me.
I couldn't sleep, so I...
I don't know how you raise your kids, Brewster, but I...
What's that you're holding there?
Just an interesting rock formation I found.
I don't like my kids staying up until all hours of the night.
I'm sorry.
Hank.
What is it, Peg?
Hank, it's Joey. He's dead.
Cool. Let me go see.
Don't go, dad. You don't have to go, Mr. Brewster.
Go home, kids.
Okay, other kid.
Sand, it's coming in. Oh, no.
Oh, no. These idiots again.
We had to whack a guy, mom.
It's all right, mom. We got it. We walked and got it.
And Joe Gamble was killed.
Killed? Joe tried to hurt Timmy. It didn't want Timmy to be hurt.
It?
Yeah.
I plugged it in.
I don't want this thing here.
Take it back. Get rid of it. Do you understand? Get rid of it this minute. I don't care.
It's the Kappas. Muggsy must have sang like a canary.
It's the ambulance for Joe Ginn.
He'll have to wait.
He has a real screen absence.
Get it out now.
Tell her to put a sock in it? Okay, blob.
Don't be worried, mother. We can't take her down to the house tonight. It won't let us.
It has to watch dragnet.
Yay!
Yay! You sure he's dead now?
Oh, yeah.
Yay!
If there's anything we can do, Peg, let us know.
Thanks, Hank. You've just been wonderful.
Take good care of your mother, Tim.
Good night.
Uncle Fester, grief counselor.
I'm sorry, Mrs. Gamble. There was nothing that could be done.
He must have died instantly in this chair.
I warned him if he kept on living in this room.
I know. I've turned thanks a lot.
His sitting was out of control by the end.
Dang.
Heartbroken, his Jim Beam distributor moves on.
I dropped my doughnut.
Honey, I'm wearing my Sears robe.
Dave.
Good morning. Hi, folks.
How are you all doing tonight?
It's grown, hasn't it?
We've had a night to think about it. What are we to do?
Law police.
Don't let anyone in, Mother.
Don't let anyone in.
You take a nap, toots. We'll handle this.
Can I borrow a cup of sand?
Yes, Freda.
Oh, there you are.
The way kids drink milk. I'm all out of it.
Do you have any?
I'm sorry, Freda. The boys just drank the last drop.
Is something the matter?
I'm not feeling very well.
That's why I didn't invite you in.
I'm afraid I wouldn't be very good company.
Oh, of course, dear.
Did you hear about Joe Gamble?
Yes.
Amazing.
To be sitting in a chair reading and to go like that.
He was still so young.
I wish I could say I was heartbroken, but I'm not.
He treated Peg and the boy miserably.
Well, thanks anyway.
I have got to get a restraining order.
You haven't moved since you left, Mom.
All right, listen. I want answers. Do you understand? I must have answers.
Don't be worried, Mother. Please.
What is this thing that's come into our lives? Will you answer me?
Why did it come here?
What does it intend to do? What have you kids got to do with it?
We have to keep it safe and warm until tonight.
We've got to do what it wants us to do until tonight.
Why tonight?
What's his bowling night?
Do you hear your father? Why tonight?
Look, I'm trying to be patient. I'm trying to understand, but I'm scared.
Do you understand? Your mother's scared.
Don't be scared, Mother.
How does it tell you and why?
I don't think you'd understand.
I'll just go wish myself into the cornfield.
It's an old friend of the glowing brains calling long distance.
Hello?
Please, don't be upset.
That's a good idea. Okay!
We have to hide it.
Come on.
Oh, yes, Major. I was just on my way to the laboratory.
Well, because I have to go, sir.
What?
Laboratory? Oh.
Yes, sir. Yes, I see. Right away.
There's only three pastries left on the train. I've got to get down to the office.
That was the Major alerting me. They're launching the Thunderer.
Do you know when? Tonight.
Tonight? Then what the children meant?
Yeah, where are they?
They just left.
At least the trailer has a nice deck.
Uh-huh.
Well, I'd call them if I could remember their names. Timmy?
Bruiser! Hey, Bruiser!
Hey, do you want to lift down to the lab?
Yeah, I thought this being your first day here, I'd drive you down to the lab, show you around, introduce you.
Where'd the kids go?
They went over to the embankment.
Hey, what's the matter?
I can get Cousin Ed to drive you later.
Sheer Cliffs, a new way to office.
Bud! Ken!
The sure-footed executive goat.
Bud! Ken! Wait!
The Blob's still in the house. That's the pot roast for tonight.
Don't leave me alone with your mother.
I think they're having lunch with Smaug.
Yes, yeah, he is a big pink dork.
Oh, hi, Dad.
I just heard about the launching of the Thunderhead tonight.
You knew before I did, didn't you?
Yes.
For I am Bud.
Who invited the suit?
Well, I suppose.
And the editor comes to the writer's rescue.
But the circus must go on!
Now, what was it, Doya? Something about the Thunder?
Yes, sir. I'm glad you're here, Dr. Worman.
What I'm about to say, while it needs explanation from someone with the greatest scientific mind in mind, I...
Go on, Brewster. What is it?
Oppenheimer took my stapler.
I believe the Thunder will never get off the ground.
What?
That's a pretty wild statement to make, Brewster.
Unless you know something we don't know. If you're proof of sabotage?
Whatever either of you is thinking, you're wrong.
It's beyond understanding.
Wow.
Last night, my two children, small boys...
Became small frogs.
Last night, down on the beach, they found something with...
Get the belt, Dad.
Don't make me leave my bike in the driveway.
Where the devil did you get in here? Top security for everyone but children, eh?
Hello, Dad.
Hello, Agent X3. I mean, Son.
Is that your boy?
Without getting into it, I'll say yes for now.
So there you are. Sorry, Colonel. I don't know how I got passes.
Neither do I. Take him out.
Sir!
Bye, Dad.
Your boy will be outside. You can take him home in a minute. Now, what were you saying?
I like the gravy in the cafeteria.
Dad.
What's the matter, Bruce?
Quick, say a prayer to St. Blaze.
Hey, General, I can draw Snuffy Smith. Lookie.
I can peaches, preserves, what?
Go find out what he put on his job application under "Do you drink a lot?"
[Music]
Weekends on the Cape. Loose fit. The J. Crew Boatneck.
And Bud continues his cigarette smuggling operation.
Every minute of my life is a gift, Earl.
Match with J. Crew Bike. $8,000.
I want a pillow between us.
What's the matter? There's something wrong with the steering wheel.
Stop it!
I'm not doing it on purpose.
You can't stop us. There's no brakes.
Next time, get a truck with brakes.
Get off the brakes, Sir. The steering wheel's coming.
And the cigarette lighter is broken.
Jeez, you have one sherry back at the restaurant. Look.
Would you stop it?
They're going off the road. Watch out.
Don't let it fall at all.
Have you tried more thrilling music than this?
What happened?
Well, ultimately, I think you're a spaz, Earl.
You almost ran into the ocean, didn't you?
Where's the nearest phone, kid?
There's a gas station down the road about a mile.
Steering rod's split wide open, and the brake's gone.
Anything I can do to help? I have my bike.
No thanks.
What's in the truck?
Look, kid, we're in a jam. Now, please don't annoy us, will you?
I was just asking.
Well, don't ask. Look, I better stay here.
Go phone the devil. Tell him to get another truck here as soon as they can.
And phone Eagle Point. Tell them what happened.
You phone the devil?
That's what I heard.
You gonna answer your fudgicle?
Devil's office.
Hello? Hello?
No, he went down to Georgia looking for a soul to steal.
Operator? Operator?
Hello?
Yes, this is Sergeant Cooper speaking.
Cat making crank calls.
Hello?
Operator?
So operators aren't standing by.
I figured.
Hi.
They're lucky. They got ice cream and everything.
Mine's bacon.
Mine's horseradish.
Oh, wow.
Oh, my.
Producers had a very strange idea that Jackie Coogan was hot.
Eddy!
I'm going to get my bikini area waxed.
I guess she's still down on the beach.
Oh, I'll find her, huh?
Oh, wow.
Eddy!
Look, it's a giant beach chicken.
Oh, it's just Jackie Coogan.
He and Buddy Hackett are going to do a production of "Old Calcutta" soon.
He ran all the way to the sound stage.
Eddy!
(
Hi, Daddy.
You're scared, honey. I didn't know where you were.
I found your jacket and a towel back on the beach.
Come on, Daddy. Let's go for a swim. I haven't been all day.
Wait a minute, honey. What are you doing in there all alone?
Just playing, Daddy. It's so nice out.
I bet the water's warm.
Come on, let's go for a swim.
What's the matter with you, honey?
What are you looking back in there for?
I mean...
Nothing, Daddy. I'm not looking at anything. Honest.
Eddy, honey.
Don't start the new Bohemians.
What's in there?
Nothing, Daddy. Just an old cave.
Come on, let's get out of here.
I will, honey, as soon as I find out what this is all about.
Don't, Daddy. Please. Please.
Not in those shorts, Daddy.
So what if John Kennedy had married Jackie Coogan?
Huh? You ever think about that?
Oh, Tinkerbell. Tone it down a bit.
I guess it just would have been an entirely different White House, is my point.
Okay. Thank you.
You know.
Thanks.
When a bald man tries to run.
Yep.
Put a light bulb under his tongue.
This is the exact moment he became Uncle Fester.
And lo, he put his head in a vise and slept on a bed of nails.
Hello, dear.
You're wearing that, huh?
You find Eddy?
Eddy?
What's the matter, Hank? What's happened?
I just saw myself in the mirror.
Nothing, I want swimming.
Hm.
We better have another weenie roast.
[Door creaks open]
Mike! Servo!
Fashion means Coogan!
Uh, guys? Where'd you go?
Oh, there you are! J-Wiz!
Ow! Ow!
What are you doing?
Come on!
Get up there!
Jeez, what's the matter?
Mike! Servo!
Fashion means Coogan!
He does?
Yeah.
Okay. I'm gonna go finish my sandwich.
Me too.
No!
What?
I design more great clothes for Jackie Coogan,
and I have sketches, and you guys have to look at 'em!
I don't wanna!
Yes!
Oh!
Okay, where are the dumb things?
Great!
Come on, Mike, you know the drill. Pick up the cards.
Stupid cards and pictures and Jackie Coogan.
Ah!
Mr. Coogan's unselfconsciously feminine robe
gave me the courage to make him this tight, black,
knit little number with matching clutch.
Whoa!
Jackie's smashing-looking short shorts
were the inspiration for this German dance-all outfit
with 100% cowhide riding crop.
Ooh!
Let's talk lingerie!
I don't wanna!
Coogan gets coquettish in this gauzy baby doll
with frilly peek-a-boo panty.
Oh, come on, girl.
I mean, okay, Coogan wore some goofy outfits in this movie,
but can't we leave him with a modicum of dignity?
No! No, we can't, Mike.
I'm hurting, I've got to lash out,
and we're gonna see this thing through to the end.
Ooh.
Next card!
Oh!
Here's the ultra-dignified Mr. Coogan
getting a teensy bit naughty
in this French cut thong singlet.
Smart on the beach or poolside?
He's got a lot of anger.
You'd better come back later.
Want to see even more of Jackie?
This crocheted banana warmer should do the trick.
No! No! No!
The children are nestled, all snug in their double-wide.
I should wake 'em up and yell at 'em.
Well, it's 1963.
Let's get in line for Beanie Babies.
She's been asked out so many times by Seinfeld.
So in this movie, it wasn't a big deal to have your own trailer.
Ten horses riding west, two days.
Everyone have their pop rocks? Good.
The Symbionese Liberation Children.
Is Barney being created here?
(laughs)
Oh, why didn't they tell me about Earth Pizzas?
Oh.
Want to skip rope?
(music)
Blob, could we schedule these for daytime, please?
Well, yeah, I know. Well, geez, you don't have to call me that.
Pete Sampras, a rare moment with his tongue in his head.
Not appearing in this film.
I hope Pa gets here soon.
Yeah, yeah, it's funny, but you told us that one already.
We have to go now.
Already?
Yes, it's time. The other children have already started.
Come on.
Hey, hey, you gonna change my box ever?
345.
Still no hair.
Foam.
Mother.
Out.
Out of order.
430.
Had small heart attack.
Johnson.
Stuck in zipper.
In hospital.
Early cult of the Franklin Planner here.
Now, I pride myself in knowing a little bit about permutations and combinations.
As you say, this may all be coincidence.
I've studied these reports again and again, and I agree there seems to be no connection between any of these events.
I've just been smoking.
That's what makes it so incredible.
Except there's one brightly colored thread that runs throughout the day tying all these events together.
I couldn't find any link.
Now, listen, Howard.
In the presence of his little boy, technician Brewster collapses.
A few hours later, according to this truck driver...
I'm bald.
As a child watches from his bicycle, the truck runs off the road.
Ah.
Two children watch a sentry, try to phone for help, and fail.
Johnson goes searching for his little daughter on the beach, collapses, and can't remember anything.
Ah.
I know all that.
You're just saying what we already know.
Now, just a second.
Can't you see?
A child or children was present at each of these events today.
Well, what if that's so? What are you driving at?
I don't know.
Children have hair.
It's all here in black and white.
Children, children, children.
What can the children have to do with it?
You know, I'm trying to solve a crisis, and all you do is smoke and criticize.
Has Brewster left the dispensary?
No. Doctor wants him to stay overnight.
Why?
Well, on the surface, everything seems calm.
And bald.
Yet all day, the unexpected, like pebbles dropping one by one, ruffling the surface.
I don't agree, sir. I think it's more like dew on morning pebbles.
Well, within an hour, the thunder will be launched.
I better get going.
I'll see you at the blockhouse.
All right.
Come on, monoxidil. Kick in.
Maybe a permanent would help.
Oh, yeah.
Where's the other armhole, Tam? And how do you get these things on?
Hey, cue ball. How's it going?
Is that hair?
Gate two. Laboratory three.
Did they just learn to count in the fifties or what?
Okay. In and out before Captain Kangaroo.
Ah, that was a lucky break. You could wait around for years and never have that happen.
Lucy.
Pump nine, sir.
God.
Where is it?
Why did you let those children inside here?
Dr. Woman, what children?
At least half a dozen children just walked out of that gate.
Dr. Woman? Is that his name?
Oh, no, sir. No, there haven't been any children around here.
Besides, the gate's locked.
Here, take a look, Dr. Woman.
Sue?
Also, sometimes when you're bald, random thoughts bombard your head and just worm their way in.
You look fine. We're gonna be late for the ballet.
I thought the doctor told you to stay overnight.
I wanted to be at the launching. Do you want to see me about something?
Is my hair thinning?
What did you tell the doctor about this morning?
Truth? That I fainted.
I'm a puss.
The matter of your voice?
I didn't tell him about that. Why should I? Wasn't important.
Total paralysis of the throat muscle's not important.
Brewster, you see, a man of science is like a deep-sea diver.
He must be afraid to walk down what's dark and frightening in the hopes of scooping up a handful of truth.
I think I just got the bends from that analogy.
Brewster, this morning, what did you want to tell us about the children?
I wanted to tell you where did the children play.
I made the obvious deductions. They don't seem to add up.
Can't speak up.
I remember very well what you said this morning.
What did I say?
There may be trouble launching the thunderer.
If all the stalls are taken, yes.
Obvious deduction. Spy on our midst.
Would you mind having some sort of expression while I'm talking to you? It'd make me feel better.
A few minutes ago in front of the powerhouse.
I ate half my sandwich.
I saw the incredible, the unbelievable.
A gibbon making flan.
Spies do not work in unbelievable ways.
Always through counterintelligence can be drawn logical conclusions.
But what I saw a group of children do a few minutes ago is something for which there is no name.
Unless you can name it.
Let's call it Dave.
I can't tell you anything.
I see.
So don't tell Baldy. That's the game.
Do you mean your voice would become paralyzed again if you should tell me that some force still unknown to man has been able through children to shatter a steering rod?
To take away a man's mind?
Another man's voice?
To allow a boy to walk through a locked gate?
I don't understand.
Nothing's happening to you as you tell me this.
You're losing a little hair, but...
That's because I'm talking to someone who also knows the truth.
Now, I wonder what would happen if I would try to tell someone else.
Uh, Table, what would happen if I try to tell you this?
Just to satisfy my scientific curiosity.
I'm gonna call Red Hot Nurses.
Uh, you know, I was kinda busy tying my tie when you came in. Is this gonna take much longer?
Hello?
You really can't have too many gray talky scenes.
Just as I thought. Dead.
Where is it now, Brewster?
In a cave.
What does it look like?
Well, it's got a good personality.
I can't describe it.
The hideous part is it's making the children obey its every command.
The children are completely in its power.
So you're saying I'm bald?
Then where in the power of the children?
We need to know where do the children play.
You know, this doesn't look like a very safe place for the children.
Haltensey.
Sorry.
I can't believe you like making love at midnight at the dunes on the Cape. This is gonna be great.
I warn you, Doctor. I can't be held accountable for what might happen if you go in there.
It's really grody.
I'm ready if you are.
Alright.
And the scientists go to lay their eggs in the sand.
Is someone here to see Grandma Blob?
Jabba the Hutt really let himself go.
Ah, finally we meet, sack of mucus.
Hola, habla ingles.
My life is more than half over.
The worst you can do to me is to kill me.
I'm willing to face that if I can just know why you're here.
Why you've taken our children and made them do your work.
But why, sir?
I've spent a lifetime in the search for truth and knowledge.
And hair.
Trying to make this world a better place.
A world where the very children you're controlling can live in peace instead of fear.
I'm their friend.
I beg of you, tell me what you want of them, what you're making them do.
Could I have some marshmallows?
Is there no man on this earth who has the wisdom and innocence of a child?
Joe Besser, maybe?
(Snores)
Dave, better hurry to the launcher.
Yeah, the world's not going to end itself, huh?
You sure Dr. Warman hasn't called in?
It was, I've called everywhere.
Ow.
Still no pulse.
Gentlemen, roll your spitballs.
Paul!
Wow, a soccer mom pioneer.
Transmission, band A.
Motor reception, 10 by 10.
Long tape warm, isn't it?
Transmission, band B.
Motor reception, 10 by 10.
The Dinky Rocket Show.
Damn, they towed my tripe.
How did you kids get in here?
We're leaving now.
Who opened that lock?
We don't know.
I don't know how you managed to get past me, but I'll give you just two seconds to get out of here.
And back!
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh.
You kids with your hula hoops and your Rosenbergs and your communist agendas and shooting down Gary Powers.
Ah.
Colonel, will you initial this?
It's for my wife, she's a really big fan of yours.
Ow, how did I do that?
I'm afraid we can't wait for Dr. Warman.
Okay, how's it look?
Everything's checked out.
You're positive?
Absolutely.
Yeah, some guy came through, I forgot to sign him in.
Hold on here, you.
Yeah, just go on through, whatever.
Hey, kids.
Yeah?
How'd you get in here?
Oh, we just walked in.
Come on, I didn't see you sneak past.
I know you didn't.
Oh, come on now, get out of here.
On the double, don't come back, now, you understand?
Bye.
Adorable little spies, they're just precious.
Check procedures terminated.
Five minutes, stand by.
Yeah, I heard.
Five minutes.
Clear the site.
Except for Danny Ray, Steve, and Tim, apparently.
Indiana wants us.
Lord, we can't go back there.
I don't know who scheduled a fire drill right before the launching.
That way we could...
Clear the site.
Anyone know what's down here?
I mean, we could...
Area security check.
Right.
Gate A locked.
Average suburban family to the rescue.
Darn, I let more commies in.
I can't believe you said that about my mother.
Just so mad.
I can hold it, I can hold it.
Radar report on target.
Optical tracking report on target.
I'm awake.
Clear for countdown.
You're just in time, Dr. Warman.
Dr. Warman, where have you been?
You had me worried.
It's all right, I can't explain.
Everything checked out.
Everything looks good.
Don't bother me, I'm copying Bill's notes.
Clear the area.
And if your area's not clear, see your doctor.
Clear area.
You guys like me.
Start the timer.
The burrito will be ready in ten seconds.
Sixty seconds to firing.
Stand by to fire.
Stand by.
Fifty.
I think. I don't know.
Well, at least we got powdered orange drink out of all this hoo-ha.
Forty.
Oh, this is where the children play.
Okay, all right, all right.
Another Cass Stevens song.
No mas.
Thirty.
I'm an insane elf.
Yep, this Bud's for you, ladies.
It's the young Stu Sutcliffe.
I'm Peter Graves.
Ten.
Nine.
Eight.
Seven.
Who do we appreciate?
Six.
Five.
Four.
Three.
Two.
One.
Fire.
Oh, man.
Well, close enough.
Well, now that you've blown all our tax money, can you fill a few potholes?
Oh, and recess is over too.
Okay, communism is better.
Check the old firing and report instantly.
What could have happened?
The children of what?
The children.
You better come along with us right now.
Quick, everybody grab jobs in the private sector.
Well, that didn't work, man.
Let's hunt for sand dollars.
Gidget in rat patrol.
The magnificent seven-year-olds.
Well, we'll just say operation blow up the rocket on the launch pad was a huge success.
All right, children, get away.
Don't come any closer.
Oh, damn that Dr. Spock.
Hello, Dad.
Why did you bring him?
He's a little bit too young for a job.
Hello, Dad. Why did you bring him?
We didn't want them here.
Don't you understand? Something has to be done.
Now, look, those men are going inside that cave.
Not yet.
There's no use trying to reason with them. They don't understand.
Ken! Ken!
All right, parents, just run to the side.
Put on a coat if you're gonna take over the world.
Is that thing in there?
Ken, for my sake.
Don't worry, Mother.
Edie, Edie, please get away from there. I beg you.
I can't, Mother. Not yet.
Why are you siding with Ed against us? We're your parents. We love you.
Tim, please, for my sake.
Children, I'm your friend.
Uncle Baldor.
I wouldn't ask you to do anything that I didn't feel was necessary.
Think of your parents, the people at the project.
Your country may be in terrible danger.
The Thunderer is useless. I don't believe you know what you've done.
We know.
We don't have to yell.
Children, listen.
Colonel Manly has a daughter of his own. I have a son.
We wouldn't ask you to do any more than we'd ask our own children.
So please get away from that cave and let Colonel Manly and his men go in.
All right, men. Move them out of there.
Marlon Brando's dancing.
One singular sensation.
Every little move he makes.
Earth versus Nougat.
Olly-gomath.
Get those kids out of there.
Hey.
It's Saint Elmo's fire.
You know, first Cat Stevens, now John Parr. You're on thin ice, Cat.
Sorry.
I'm a little heavier now. It's kind of hard.
Nope, this ain't happening. Too much seafood.
What the hell got into us? I mean, man, I'd ground us.
I don't understand.
Why did it destroy the thunder?
Why?
It had to. Because the world wasn't ready to do it.
The world?
What do you mean, the world?
The children, all over the world, they did what we did in every country.
Give me the warheads in Moscow and Prague and London. They're all useless?
Yes.
But they overlooked Canada, and Canada takes over the world. Mandatory tukes and backbaking.
Oh, God.
Do you know if it'll ever come back again?
Can we use our chemical stockpiles?
I don't know.
I am crashing from a pop tart high.
The world is having a second chance.
So, no military. You guys want to start a band or something?
Wait till he's out of sight, then load up Thunder or Number Two.
This is all that's left of St. Matthew's original screenplay.
But, you know, once you enter the kingdom of heaven, you get your hand stamped so you can leave and enter.
So right now, St. Matthew's poolside at the Polo Lounge, smoking cigars at Shane Black and Jerry Bruckheimer.
Boy, that St. Matthew is a cracking good screenwriter, don't you think?
Oh, he sure is.
Say, what do you know? It's that blob from the movie.
The blob sent from heaven.
Well, he must want us to get rid of our nuclear bombs.
He says yes.
I don't think we have any nuclear bombs, Mr. Holy Blob.
Crow, any nuclear bombs?
Oh, now you're one, Mike.
Servo, you got any?
No, no, none at all. No nuclear bombs here. Sorry, no siree.
Well, maybe one.
Servo!
I wouldn't call it a nuclear bomb, per se.
It's really more of like a neutron device, you know, when you put...
What's the big deal, you guys?
Look, I like to cruise estate sales. I bought it at one of those.
Thought it might be a good deterrent against you guys someday.
Wow.
All right, geez, I'll go to my room and get it. It's under the bed.
Stupid, peace-loving blob from heaven anyway. I don't know.
Oh, oops, Pearl's calling, so...
So, get you a beer, Holy Blob? Coming right up.
Ten, nine, eight, seven, six, three, four...
Oh, damn it, let me start again. Ten, nine...
You want to see some real rocketry, Major Nelson?
Six, five, four, three, two, one, zero...
Lift off, we have lift off.
It's beautiful, isn't it?
Yes, it is. It sure is.
Oh, oh, oh, dear. I was supposed to be in that, wasn't I?
Oh, my.
You see, the thing is, I forgot my three musketeers, so I got out of the capsule,
because all there was in the capsule was ten to eat,
and I knew I'd get hungry for my chocolaty three musketeers,
so I got out of the capsule in order to get my three musketeers,
and I must have forgotten to get back in.
Sorry, baby.
That means no one is steering the rocket.
It might start turning and heading straight for us.
No!
I love you greatly.
I love you too, Bobo.
Okay.
Nice meeting you.
Really, it was quite nice.
[Laughing]
[Music]